<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss  xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" 
      xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" 
      xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" 
      xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" 
      version="2.0">
<channel>
<title>HSP 2025</title>
<link>https://hsp2025.github.io/posts.html</link>
<atom:link href="https://hsp2025.github.io/posts.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
<description>UMD HSP 2025</description>
<image>
<url>https://hsp2025.github.io/files/logos/icon.png</url>
<title>HSP 2025</title>
<link>https://hsp2025.github.io/posts.html</link>
</image>
<generator>quarto-1.5.55</generator>
<lastBuildDate>Wed, 09 Oct 2024 04:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
<item>
  <title>Special Session ‘Demo’ Period</title>
  <dc:creator>HSP Committee</dc:creator>
  <link>https://hsp2025.github.io/posts/demo/</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 




<p><img src="https://hsp2025.github.io/posts/demo/bridge.jpeg" class="preview-image img-fluid"></p>
<p>We are excited to introduce a new feature at the Annual Conference on Human Sentence Processing (HSP), as part of our NSF-funded special session, ’‘<strong>Connecting Minds, Building Bridges: Community Outreach in Language Processing Research</strong>.’’ For the first time, we will host a ‘’Demo’’’ period, providing space for hands-on outreach demonstrations that go beyond traditional posters or talks. This is an opportunity to showcase work that can only be fully appreciated through direct experience—such as sounds, multimedia presentations, interactive activities for children, and more.</p>
<p>While the session will focus on live demonstrations, abstracts are required to evaluate and understand the content of these presentations. These abstracts should serve as descriptions of your planned activities and may differ in structure from those typically submitted for traditional poster sessions. We invite abstracts that showcase community-engagement activities in psycholinguistics. These demos should highlight outreach projects that researchers are involved in, featuring the stakeholders you work with—whether they be schools, community organizations, or broader public groups. Presenting real-world examples of successful outreach will illustrate how psycholinguistic research can directly benefit communities and foster meaningful collaboration.</p>
<p>In addition to showcasing ongoing efforts, we also encourage abstracts that propose new community engagement initiatives. These proposals can outline your planned activities, highlighting how you aim to involve key stakeholders and promote greater interaction between the scientific community and the public.</p>
<p>We encourage abstracts that highlight creative outreach initiatives, interactive demonstrations, and alternative ways of presenting research aligned with the theme of community engagement. Abstracts should include a brief description of the demo, its objectives, and how it connects to the special session theme.</p>
<p>Although we are primarily encouraging demos that highlight creative outreach initiatives and community engagement activities, we also welcome submissions that present innovative experimental methods or approaches. If you have a demonstration that is best understood through direct experience, such as a new experimental technique, this demo period could be an excellent opportunity to share it with the community.</p>
<p>Presenters of the demos will have approximately 1 hour and 20 minutes for their presentations, which may overlap with a poster session to maximize audience engagement.</p>
<p>Since this is a new feature, please include any logistical needs (e.g., table, electricity, poster board, etc.) to ensure the space is prepared for your demonstration. All demo abstracts should adhere to the same formatting requirements as traditional abstracts for talks and posters.</p>
<p>This demo period provides a unique opportunity for researchers to showcase how their work connects with broader societal needs. By sharing innovative and interactive outreach efforts, participants can highlight the practical, real-world relevance of psycholinguistic research. These demonstrations will help other researchers recognize the potential for their own work to reach and engage the public, fostering stronger connections between the scientific community and the communities we aim to serve.</p>
<p>We look forward to your submissions and the exciting potential these demos have to inspire and engage.</p>



 ]]></description>
  <category>frontpage</category>
  <category>demo</category>
  <category>cfp</category>
  <guid>https://hsp2025.github.io/posts/demo/</guid>
  <pubDate>Wed, 09 Oct 2024 04:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Special Session Information</title>
  <dc:creator>HSP Committee</dc:creator>
  <link>https://hsp2025.github.io/posts/special-session/</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 




<section id="connecting-minds-building-bridges-community-outreach-in-language-processing-research" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="connecting-minds-building-bridges-community-outreach-in-language-processing-research">Connecting Minds, Building Bridges: Community Outreach in Language Processing Research</h2>
<p>This year’s special session focuses on enhancing psycholinguists’ ability to appreciate the link between their scientific interests and the needs of the wider community.</p>
<ul>
<li>How does our work benefit society?</li>
<li>How does collaborating with community partners enable research that is informed by societal needs and yield impact outside the academy?</li>
<li>How can we collaborate with community organizations such as schools, healthcare practices, museums, advocacy groups, and policy makers?</li>
<li>How can we overcome barriers and challenges associated with this research model, such as establishing public partnerships, aligning research goals with societal interests, and improving public communication?</li>
</ul>
<p>For the first time, we will host a ‘’Demo’’’ period, providing space for hands-on outreach demonstrations that go beyond traditional posters or talks. This is an opportunity to showcase work that can only be fully appreciated through direct experience—such as sounds, multimedia presentations, interactive activities for children, and more. This demo period aims to foster community engagement by showcasing innovative outreach activities and experimental methods that benefit from hands-on experience. Researchers are encouraged to submit abstracts that highlight creative initiatives, interactive demonstrations, and alternative presentations aligned with our conference theme. View detailed abstract submission instructions for our special session <a href="../demo/index.html">‘’Demo period’’</a>..</p>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>special session</category>
  <category>bridges</category>
  <category>community outreach</category>
  <guid>https://hsp2025.github.io/posts/special-session/</guid>
  <pubDate>Wed, 09 Oct 2024 04:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Code of Conduct</title>
  <dc:creator>HSP Committee</dc:creator>
  <link>https://hsp2025.github.io/posts/code/</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 




<p>HSP 2025 is committed to providing a safe, harassment-free conference experience for everyone, regardless of gender, gender identity, sexual orientation, disability, physical appearance, body size, race, age, religion, language use, ethnicity, or nationality. We do not tolerate harassment of any kind. Participants violating these rules may be sanctioned or expelled at the discretion of the conference organizers.</p>
<p><strong>Harassment includes, but is not limited to:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Verbal comments that reinforce social hierarchies based on gender, sexual orientation, disability, appearance, race, age, religion, or nationality</li>
<li>Displaying sexual images in public spaces</li>
<li>Deliberate intimidation, stalking, or following</li>
<li>Behaviors aimed at making individuals or groups feel unwelcome, or encouraging ostracism</li>
<li>Harassing photography or recording</li>
<li>Disruption of talks or other events</li>
<li>Inappropriate physical contact</li>
<li>Unwanted sexual attention</li>
<li>Advocating for or encouraging any of the above behaviors</li>
</ul>
<p>These behaviors are unacceptable during both in-person interactions and in online spaces (e.g., event-related chats or social media).</p>
<section id="enforcement" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="enforcement">Enforcement</h2>
<p>Participants who are asked to stop harassing behavior must comply immediately. Event organizers may take any action necessary to maintain a welcoming environment, including issuing warnings, expelling offenders, barring future participation, reporting incidents to the offender’s institution or funding agencies, or contacting law enforcement.</p>
<p>Organizers may take action against any behavior that disrupts the event or creates a hostile environment.</p>
<p>We expect participants to follow these rules at all event venues (including online platforms like Zoom) and during social activities. While these rules apply to event-related activities, we encourage participants to uphold these standards outside of event activities as well.</p>
</section>
<section id="reporting" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="reporting">Reporting</h2>
<p>If you or anyone else feels unsafe or unwelcome, please report the incident to conference staff immediately. Violations of the Code of Conduct detract from the experience for everyone, and we want to ensure a positive, inclusive environment. You can report an incident by contacting any of the following conference staff:</p>
<ul>
<li>Jared Novick: <script type="text/javascript">
<!--
h='&#x75;&#x6d;&#100;&#46;&#x65;&#100;&#x75;';a='&#64;';n='&#106;&#110;&#x6f;&#118;&#x69;&#x63;&#x6b;&#x31;';e=n+a+h;
document.write('<a h'+'ref'+'="ma'+'ilto'+':'+e+'" clas'+'s="em' + 'ail">'+e+'<\/'+'a'+'>');
// -->
</script><noscript>jnovick1 at umd dot edu</noscript></li>
<li>Yi Ting Huang: <script type="text/javascript">
<!--
h='&#x75;&#x6d;&#100;&#46;&#x65;&#100;&#x75;';a='&#64;';n='&#x79;&#116;&#104;&#x75;&#x61;&#110;&#x67;&#x31;';e=n+a+h;
document.write('<a h'+'ref'+'="ma'+'ilto'+':'+e+'" clas'+'s="em' + 'ail">'+e+'<\/'+'a'+'>');
// -->
</script><noscript>ythuang1 at umd dot edu</noscript></li>
<li>Rochelle Newman: <script type="text/javascript">
<!--
h='&#x75;&#x6d;&#100;&#46;&#x65;&#100;&#x75;';a='&#64;';n='&#114;&#110;&#x65;&#x77;&#x6d;&#x61;&#110;&#x31;';e=n+a+h;
document.write('<a h'+'ref'+'="ma'+'ilto'+':'+e+'" clas'+'s="em' + 'ail">'+e+'<\/'+'a'+'>');
// -->
</script><noscript>rnewman1 at umd dot edu</noscript></li>
<li>Bob Slevc: <script type="text/javascript">
<!--
h='&#x75;&#x6d;&#100;&#46;&#x65;&#100;&#x75;';a='&#64;';n='&#x73;&#108;&#x65;&#118;&#x63;';e=n+a+h;
document.write('<a h'+'ref'+'="ma'+'ilto'+':'+e+'" clas'+'s="em' + 'ail">'+e+'<\/'+'a'+'>');
// -->
</script><noscript>slevc at umd dot edu</noscript></li>
<li>All Conference Organizers: <script type="text/javascript">
<!--
h='&#x75;&#x6d;&#100;&#46;&#x65;&#100;&#x75;';a='&#64;';n='&#104;&#x73;&#112;&#x2d;&#50;&#48;&#50;&#x35;';e=n+a+h;
document.write('<a h'+'ref'+'="ma'+'ilto'+':'+e+'" clas'+'s="em' + 'ail">'+e+'<\/'+'a'+'>');
// -->
</script><noscript>hsp-2025 at umd dot edu</noscript></li>
</ul>
<p>Please note that emails sent to University of Maryland addresses are public records under Maryland’s Public Information Act (PIA). For private reporting, you may also use this personal email address:</p>
<ul>
<li>Jared Novick: <script type="text/javascript">
<!--
h='&#x67;&#x6d;&#x61;&#x69;&#108;&#46;&#x63;&#x6f;&#x6d;';a='&#64;';n='&#106;&#x61;&#114;&#x65;&#100;&#46;&#110;&#x6f;&#118;&#x69;&#x63;&#x6b;';e=n+a+h;
document.write('<a h'+'ref'+'="ma'+'ilto'+':'+e+'" clas'+'s="em' + 'ail">'+e+'<\/'+'a'+'>');
// -->
</script><noscript>jared.novick at gmail dot com</noscript></li>
</ul>
<p><em>Adapted from the HSP 2024 Code of Conduct</em></p>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>code of conduct</category>
  <guid>https://hsp2025.github.io/posts/code/</guid>
  <pubDate>Wed, 09 Oct 2024 04:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Call for Papers!</title>
  <dc:creator>HSP Committee</dc:creator>
  <link>https://hsp2025.github.io/posts/cfp/</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 




<p>We invite submissions for the Annual Conference on Human Sentence Processing. In addition to soliciting abstracts for traditional podium talks and posters, we are excited to announce a new opportunity for researchers to participate in our interactive demo period.</p>
<p>This demo period aims to foster community engagement by showcasing innovative outreach activities and experimental methods that benefit from hands-on experience. Researchers are encouraged to submit abstracts that highlight creative initiatives, interactive demonstrations, and alternative presentations aligned with our conference theme. View detailed abstract submission instructions for our special session <a href="../demo/index.html">‘’Demo period’’</a>.</p>
<p>For detailed instructions on how to submit your abstracts for both traditional presentations and the new demo period, please refer to the submission guidelines.</p>
<p>We look forward to your contributions and to making this conference an engaging and impactful experience for all attendees!</p>
<section id="submission-portal" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="submission-portal">Submission Portal</h2>
<p>Abstracts should be submitted via <a href="https://app.oxfordabstracts.com/stages/76458/submitter">Oxford Abstracts</a>.</p>
</section>
<section id="abstract-submission-information" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="abstract-submission-information">Abstract Submission Information</h2>
<p>We welcome your contributions to the special session. And, as always, we invite abstracts related to language processing more generally. Abstracts may be submitted for the interactive demo session, posters, or for 20-minute podium presentations.</p>
<p>Abstracts are due on <strong>Monday, December 2, 2024 by 11:59:59pm</strong> (anywhere on earth).</p>
<!-- Abstracts are due on XXXX (anywhere on earth). -->
<p>Dr.&nbsp;Maayan Keshev has put together a <a href="https://docs.google.com/document/d/1J_amu8bT3tIcPGh_zY_M8nLq3FSRK8KNa2pZKlc0rfs/">document of tips</a> for how to write a HSP abstract.</p>
<p>For more information, please contact <script type="text/javascript">
<!--
h='&#x75;&#x6d;&#100;&#46;&#x65;&#100;&#x75;';a='&#64;';n='&#104;&#x73;&#112;&#x2d;&#50;&#48;&#50;&#x35;';e=n+a+h;
document.write('<a h'+'ref'+'="ma'+'ilto'+':'+e+'" clas'+'s="em' + 'ail">'+e+'<\/'+'a'+'>');
// -->
</script><noscript>hsp-2025 at umd dot edu</noscript>.</p>
<p>We are looking forward to seeing you March 27-29, 2025 in College Park!</p>
</section>
<section id="abstract-specifications" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="abstract-specifications">Abstract Specifications</h2>
<ul>
<li>Please upload a PDF version of your abstract.</li>
<li>Abstracts should be in letter format (8.5” x 11”), with 1-inch margins on all sides, and in Arial 11 point font.</li>
<li>The abstract itself (text) may be no longer than one page; a page containing additional figures, tables, other graphics and/or references may be included as well.</li>
<li>References should preferably be in APA format, but other formats are acceptable.</li>
<li>Abstracts should not include authors or affiliations in the PDF. Please also avoid any identifying information about the authors in the text of the abstract itself (e.g., “In our previous work, we found…”).</li>
<li>Please be sure your abstract mentions the language(s) being investigated. Do not omit the language under investigation if it is English.</li>
</ul>
<!--Include social share buttons-->
<!--
AddToAny check more: https://www.addtoany.com/buttons/for/website
Using includes will make edits easier, will only need to add or remove button here if needed.
https://quarto.org/docs/authoring/includes.html
-->
<i>Share this post:</i>
<div class="a2a_kit a2a_kit_size_32 a2a_default_style">
<p><a class="a2a_dd" href="https://www.addtoany.com/share"></a> <a class="a2a_button_linkedin"></a> <a class="a2a_button_x"></a> <a class="a2a_button_facebook"></a> <a class="a2a_button_mastodon"></a> <a class="a2a_button_whatsapp"></a> <a class="a2a_button_wechat"></a> <a class="a2a_button_sina_weibo"></a> <a class="a2a_button_copy_link"></a> <a class="a2a_button_email"></a></p>
</div>
<script async="" src="https://static.addtoany.com/menu/page.js"></script>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>frontpage</category>
  <category>call for papers</category>
  <category>cfp</category>
  <guid>https://hsp2025.github.io/posts/cfp/</guid>
  <pubDate>Wed, 09 Oct 2024 04:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://hsp2025.github.io/posts/cfp/oa.png" medium="image" type="image/png" height="67" width="144"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Travel Support</title>
  <dc:creator>HSP Committee</dc:creator>
  <link>https://hsp2025.github.io/posts/support/</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 




<p><img src="https://hsp2025.github.io/posts/support/hall.jpeg" class="preview-image img-fluid"></p>
<p>Applications for travel support are coming soon. Stay tuned for more information on how to apply for travel support to attend the conference by subscribing to <a href="https://listserv.uconn.edu/scripts/wa.exe?SUBED1=HSP-L&amp;A=1">HSP Listserv</a> or joining our <a href="https://discord.gg/zbEeF6Dzkj">Discord server</a>.</p>
<section id="equity-and-access-support" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="equity-and-access-support">Equity and Access Support</h2>
<section id="registration-supplement" class="level4">
<h4 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="registration-supplement">Registration Supplement</h4>
<p>We will subsidize the cost of attendance by covering the registration fees for approximately 55 undergraduate and graduate students, including those in UMD’s REACH Program, students from local HBCUs, MSIs, and Gallaudet University, at a rate of $150 per participant.</p>
</section>
<section id="travel-supplement" class="level4">
<h4 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="travel-supplement">Travel Supplement</h4>
<p>We will provide travel supplements of $50 each to 40 students who receive the Equity and Access Award, specifically to assist with travel costs for those coming from local HBCUs, MSIs, and Gallaudet University located outside the immediate area.</p>
</section>
</section>
<section id="graduate-student-travel-support" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="graduate-student-travel-support">Graduate Student Travel Support</h2>
<p>We will provide approximately 30 graduate student travel support at $375 per participant to defray the cost of travel to the conference.</p>
</section>
<section id="contact" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="contact">Contact</h2>
<p>Questions about funding? Contact the HSP Committee at <script type="text/javascript">
<!--
h='&#x75;&#x6d;&#100;&#46;&#x65;&#100;&#x75;';a='&#64;';n='&#104;&#x73;&#112;&#x2d;&#50;&#48;&#50;&#x35;';e=n+a+h;
document.write('<a h'+'ref'+'="ma'+'ilto'+':'+e+'" clas'+'s="em' + 'ail">'+e+'<\/'+'a'+'>');
// -->
</script><noscript>hsp-2025 at umd dot edu</noscript> or join our <a href="https://discord.gg/zbEeF6Dzkj">Discord server</a>.</p>
<!--Include social share buttons-->
<!--
AddToAny check more: https://www.addtoany.com/buttons/for/website
Using includes will make edits easier, will only need to add or remove button here if needed.
https://quarto.org/docs/authoring/includes.html
-->
<i>Share this post:</i>
<div class="a2a_kit a2a_kit_size_32 a2a_default_style">
<p><a class="a2a_dd" href="https://www.addtoany.com/share"></a> <a class="a2a_button_linkedin"></a> <a class="a2a_button_x"></a> <a class="a2a_button_facebook"></a> <a class="a2a_button_mastodon"></a> <a class="a2a_button_whatsapp"></a> <a class="a2a_button_wechat"></a> <a class="a2a_button_sina_weibo"></a> <a class="a2a_button_copy_link"></a> <a class="a2a_button_email"></a></p>
</div>
<script async="" src="https://static.addtoany.com/menu/page.js"></script>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>support</category>
  <category>travel</category>
  <guid>https://hsp2025.github.io/posts/support/</guid>
  <pubDate>Fri, 04 Oct 2024 04:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Venue</title>
  <dc:creator>HSP Committee</dc:creator>
  <link>https://hsp2025.github.io/posts/venue/</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 




<p><img src="https://hsp2025.github.io/posts/venue/stamp.jpg" class="preview-image img-fluid"></p>
<p>HSP 2025 will be held in the Adele H. Stamp Student Union building at the University of Maryland College Park.</p>
<p><img src="https://hsp2025.github.io/posts/venue/venue.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<ul>
<li>Address: 3972 Campus Dr, College Park, MD 20742</li>
<li>Talks will be held in the Grand Ballroom</li>
<li>Coffee Breaks will be served in the Grand Ballroom Lounge</li>
<li>Poster sessions will take place in the Grand Ballroom</li>
</ul>
<p><img src="https://hsp2025.github.io/posts/venue/ballroom.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<ul>
<li>Free wifi access is available through Eduroam or the <a href="https://itsupport.umd.edu/itsupport?id=kb_article_view&amp;sysparm_article=KB0012824">UMD Guest Network</a></li>
<li>ASL interpreters will provide simultaneous translation services for all talks</li>
<li>Other important locations are marked on the map below (insert map with accessible entrances/lactation rooms/bathrooms etc)</li>
</ul>
<!--Include social share buttons-->
<!--
AddToAny check more: https://www.addtoany.com/buttons/for/website
Using includes will make edits easier, will only need to add or remove button here if needed.
https://quarto.org/docs/authoring/includes.html
-->
<i>Share this post:</i>
<div class="a2a_kit a2a_kit_size_32 a2a_default_style">
<p><a class="a2a_dd" href="https://www.addtoany.com/share"></a> <a class="a2a_button_linkedin"></a> <a class="a2a_button_x"></a> <a class="a2a_button_facebook"></a> <a class="a2a_button_mastodon"></a> <a class="a2a_button_whatsapp"></a> <a class="a2a_button_wechat"></a> <a class="a2a_button_sina_weibo"></a> <a class="a2a_button_copy_link"></a> <a class="a2a_button_email"></a></p>
</div>
<script async="" src="https://static.addtoany.com/menu/page.js"></script>



 ]]></description>
  <category>frontpage</category>
  <category>venue</category>
  <category>travel</category>
  <category>attending</category>
  <guid>https://hsp2025.github.io/posts/venue/</guid>
  <pubDate>Fri, 04 Oct 2024 04:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Social Events</title>
  <dc:creator>HSP Committee</dc:creator>
  <link>https://hsp2025.github.io/posts/social/</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 




<p><img src="https://hsp2025.github.io/posts/social/planet.jpg" class="preview-image img-fluid"></p>
<section id="social-events" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="social-events">Social Events</h3>
<p><strong>Conference Reception Party:</strong> We will have a conference reception at the Planet Word Museum in Washington, DC. 925 13th St NW, Washington, DC 20005</p>
<p>Details are coming soon!</p>
<!--Include social share buttons-->
<!--
AddToAny check more: https://www.addtoany.com/buttons/for/website
Using includes will make edits easier, will only need to add or remove button here if needed.
https://quarto.org/docs/authoring/includes.html
-->
<i>Share this post:</i>
<div class="a2a_kit a2a_kit_size_32 a2a_default_style">
<p><a class="a2a_dd" href="https://www.addtoany.com/share"></a> <a class="a2a_button_linkedin"></a> <a class="a2a_button_x"></a> <a class="a2a_button_facebook"></a> <a class="a2a_button_mastodon"></a> <a class="a2a_button_whatsapp"></a> <a class="a2a_button_wechat"></a> <a class="a2a_button_sina_weibo"></a> <a class="a2a_button_copy_link"></a> <a class="a2a_button_email"></a></p>
</div>
<script async="" src="https://static.addtoany.com/menu/page.js"></script>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>news</category>
  <category>social</category>
  <category>party</category>
  <category>reception</category>
  <category>attending</category>
  <guid>https://hsp2025.github.io/posts/social/</guid>
  <pubDate>Wed, 04 Sep 2024 04:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Food and Drink</title>
  <dc:creator>HSP Committee</dc:creator>
  <link>https://hsp2025.github.io/posts/food/</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 




<div class="columns">
<div class="column" style="width:57%;">
<section id="food-and-drink" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="food-and-drink">Food and Drink</h3>
</section>
</div><div class="column" style="width:3%;">
<!-- empty column to create gap -->
</div><div class="column" style="width:40%;">
<p><img src="https://hsp2025.github.io/posts/food/foodmap.jpg" class="preview-image img-fluid"></p>
</div>
</div>
<section id="college-park" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="college-park">College Park</h3>
<p><strong>The Board and Brew:</strong> College Park, short walk from UMD campus. Decent eats, great single origin coffees, evening brews, and the only place we know with a board game sommelier to advise you on a choice of games. Indoor and outdoor seating.</p>
<p><strong>The Hall CP:</strong> Main attraction is proximity to campus – right behind The Hotel @ UMD – and the expansive rear patio. Bar, pizzeria, and event spot created by the brother of “the Under Armour guy” (a former UMD football player). The food isn’t memorable, but on a nice evening it can be a very nice place to hang out with friends. We’ll aim to do dinner here on Thursday.</p>
<p><strong>Taqueria Habanero:</strong> In an unremarkable strip mall behind the College Park fire station, this little place has been rated (by the Fake News Washington Post) as the best place to get tacos in the entire DC area. We agree!</p>
<p><strong>Northwest Chinese:</strong> Small place in downtown College Park that’s consistently rated as one of the best local eateries. Not your standard American Chinese fare.</p>
<p><strong>Vigilante Coffee:</strong> With shops in College Park and Hyattsville, many locals regard this hip roaster as the pinnacle of local coffee.</p>
</section>
<section id="nearby" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="nearby">Nearby</h3>
<p>The strip from College Park to Hyattsville has become surprisingly interesting for eats and drinks in recent years. You could even muster a brewery crawl via the College Park Trolley Trail bike path.</p>
<p>The beer (and more) trail. In order of distance from the UMD campus.</p>
<p><strong>Denizens Brewery:</strong> In the new Riverdale Park Station development, next to Whole Foods. Hip local brewery. Co-owner Julie Veratti and her wife started the brewery in 2014. She later ran (unsuccessfully) for Lieutenant Governor, and then was appointed by Pres Biden to the Small Business Administration. The beer’s not bad, either. Outside tables by reservation online.</p>
<p><strong>Burton’s:</strong> In the new Riverdale Park Station development, next to Whole Foods. It’s the kind of respectable-but-not-staid place we might take a visiting speaker. Also, best place in the area for taking food allergies seriously.</p>
<p><strong>Town Center Market:</strong> One of our favorite local hangouts. Next to the Riverdale Park commuter rail station. Quirky liquor store with a popular outdoor beer garden (mix of open and covered/heated), and an impressive range of craft beers on tap. And they encourage customers to bring in take-out food.</p>
<p><strong>2Fifty Texas BBQ:</strong> Same block as Town Center Market. Since opening a couple of years ago it has leapt to the top of lists of best places for BBQ in the DC area. And that’s not damning with faint praise. Recommended to order ahead, as they’re so popular they often sell out.</p>
<p><strong>Busboys &amp; Poets:</strong> Restaurant, bar, and lefty bookstore. It’s where some UMD grad students were surprised to find Noam Chomsky when they showed up late one evening a few years ago (true story!).</p>
<p><strong>Franklin’s Brewery &amp; General Store:</strong> The best combination brew pub and toy store (really!) you will ever encounter. This local favorite is credited with starting the local renaissance 20 years ago. Their big outdoor seating area (“Quarantiki Bar”), opened during the pandemic, may be back by late March.</p>
<p><strong>Streetcar 82 Brewery:</strong> Named after the trolley line that is now a bike path, this small brewery is run by some Gallaudet U grads and is the only brewery we know that gets quieter over the course of the evening, as the number of ASL speakers increases. Good outdoor seating. No food.</p>
<p><strong>Maryland Meadworks:</strong> There’s more to mead than you thought! They team up with the bakery next door for weekend brunches. Another local favorite.</p>
</section>
<section id="college-park-parkrun" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="college-park-parkrun">College Park parkrun</h2>
<p>Join us at 9am Saturday morning for College Park parkrun, a free, weekly 5K run/walk on College Park’s prettiest trail, just to the north of the UMD campus. It’s all about creating a healthy community, serving kids and seniors, speedy athletes and folks who are taking a stroll with friends. It has taken place every week, year round, since 2016, becoming one of the main ways that locals from different backgrounds come together. Register for a free personal barcode, and then just show up by around 8:50 at Acredale Community Park (8:40 if you want to find parking right at the park). Reachable from campus or local hotels on foot via the Paint Branch Trail.</p>
</section>
<section id="planet-word-museum" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="planet-word-museum">Planet Word Museum</h2>
<p>Planet Word is the hottest new addition to the Washington DC museum scene. And it’s all about language! It was designed in consultation with lots of language experts. Nab a free ticket if you can (or try a walk up and hope for the best), and head to the museum that will leave you feeling that it’s cool to be a language nerd!</p>
<p>Starting Summer 2022, UMD’s Language Science Center will be offering a cool new summer research and science communication course at the museum, in collaboration with Gallaudet University and Howard University, supported by NSF. Got interested students? Let us know.</p>
<!--Include social share buttons-->
<!--
AddToAny check more: https://www.addtoany.com/buttons/for/website
Using includes will make edits easier, will only need to add or remove button here if needed.
https://quarto.org/docs/authoring/includes.html
-->
<i>Share this post:</i>
<div class="a2a_kit a2a_kit_size_32 a2a_default_style">
<p><a class="a2a_dd" href="https://www.addtoany.com/share"></a> <a class="a2a_button_linkedin"></a> <a class="a2a_button_x"></a> <a class="a2a_button_facebook"></a> <a class="a2a_button_mastodon"></a> <a class="a2a_button_whatsapp"></a> <a class="a2a_button_wechat"></a> <a class="a2a_button_sina_weibo"></a> <a class="a2a_button_copy_link"></a> <a class="a2a_button_email"></a></p>
</div>
<script async="" src="https://static.addtoany.com/menu/page.js"></script>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>news</category>
  <category>food</category>
  <category>college park</category>
  <category>attending</category>
  <guid>https://hsp2025.github.io/posts/food/</guid>
  <pubDate>Wed, 04 Sep 2024 04:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Travel and Accomodation</title>
  <dc:creator>HSP Committee</dc:creator>
  <link>https://hsp2025.github.io/posts/travel/</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 




<p><img src="https://hsp2025.github.io/posts/travel/union.jpg" class="preview-image img-fluid"></p>
<section id="travel-and-accomodation" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="travel-and-accomodation">Travel and Accomodation</h2>
<p>The conference will take place in the Grand Ballroom of the Stamp Student Union on Campus Drive. <a href="http://maps.umd.edu/map/">This interactive campus map</a> might also be helpful for navigating.</p>
<section id="from-the-metro" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="from-the-metro">From the Metro</h3>
<p>To get to College Park via the <a href="https://www.wmata.com/">DC Metro</a>, take the Green Line (direction Greenbelt) to the <a href="https://www.google.com/maps/place/38%C2%B058%2742.5%22N+76%C2%B055%2741.9%22W/@38.978463,-76.928304,15z/data=!3m1!4b1!4m2!3m1!1s0x0:0x0">College Park Station</a>. It is best to buy a reusable <a href="http://www.wmata.com/fares/smartrip/">SmarTrip card</a>. If instead you buy a new ticket for each ride, you will pay a $1 surcharge for for each ticket. One can also use <a href="https://www.wmata.com/fares/MobilePay/ApplePay.cfm">Apple Wallet</a> or <a href="https://www.wmata.com/fares/MobilePay/GooglePay.cfm">GPay</a> options. There are then two ways to get to Stamp from the Metro Station.</p>
<section id="red-shuttle-bus" class="level4">
<h4 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="red-shuttle-bus">Red Shuttle Bus</h4>
<p><a href="http://www.transportation.umd.edu/schedules.html">University of Maryland Shuttle Buses</a> to the campus leave regularly from the front (east side) of the station. This is Route 104, which stops at Regent Drive Garage - a five minute walk to the Stamp Student Union.</p>
</section>
<section id="walking-full-map" class="level4">
<h4 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="walking-full-map">Walking (full <a href="https://www.google.com/maps/dir/College+Park+Metro+Station,+College+Park,+MD/Adele+H.+Stamp+Student+Union,+3972+Campus+Dr,+College+Park,+MD+20742/@38.9855812,-76.9428363,1303m/data=!3m1!1e3!4m29!4m28!1m20!1m1!1s0x89b7c6c811d81269:0x95dda11b887323c3!2m2!1d-76.929012!2d38.975464!3m4!1m2!1d-76.9304717!2d38.9800334!3s0x89b7c6b9c5206427:0x4a465d2abd138676!3m4!1m2!1d-76.9398305!2d38.9829203!3s0x89b7c6bddfb351d3:0x55f9551aacf88a8c!3m4!1m2!1d-76.9402817!2d38.9874127!3s0x89b7c6bd4f203dbf:0xd19f5af465365300!1m5!1m1!1s0x89b7c4065ace9699:0xdc2bb57f0c8b153c!2m2!1d-76.9448867!2d38.9878244!3e2">map</a>)</h4>
<p>After exiting the turnstile in the Metro station, take <a href="https://www.google.com/maps/place/38%C2%B058%2741.8%22N+76%C2%B055%2742.5%22W/@38.978267,-76.928471,15z/data=!3m1!4b1!4m2!3m1!1s0x0:0x0">the pedestrian tunnel</a> under the train platform. Walk through the parking lot to Columbia Avenue, <a href="https://www.google.com/maps/place/38%C2%B058%2744.3%22N+76%C2%B055%2745.7%22W/@38.978977,-76.929349,15z/data=!3m1!4b1!4m2!3m1!1s0x0:0x0">turn right onto Columbia</a>, and walk north about 100m. Then turn left <a href="https://www.google.com/maps/place/38%C2%B058%2748.4%22N+76%C2%B055%2744.1%22W/@38.980112,-76.92892,15z/data=!3m1!4b1!4m2!3m1!1s0x0:0x0">from Columbia onto College Ave</a>. Walk about half a mile west on College Avenue to Route 1, known here as Baltimore Avenue. Cross Route 1 and continue straight on what is now called Regents Drive. <a href="https://www.google.com/maps/dir/Baltimore+Ave+%26+Regents+Dr,+College+Park,+MD+20740/38.9874127,-76.9402817/@38.9848657,-76.9442248,913m/data=!3m1!1e3!4m14!4m13!1m10!1m1!1s0x89b7c6be838540cd:0xb192acc460e93e6d!2m2!1d-76.937994!2d38.982171!3m4!1m2!1d-76.9398821!2d38.9830126!3s0x89b7c6bddfb351d3:0x55f9551aacf88a8c!1m0!3e2">Walk along Regents drive</a>, which curves from westward to northward, for 700m, until you reach a traffic circle (called “The M”). Turn left, and walk 400m westward. The Stamp will be on your right, the grand ballroom is on the first floor of the Stamp Student Union.</p>
</section>
</section>
<section id="air-travel" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="air-travel">Air travel</h3>
<p>Guests traveling to College Park by air have a choice of three airports: Reagan Washington National Airport (DCA), Baltimore-Washington International Airport (BWI), and (least conveniently) Dulles International Airport (IAD).</p>
<section id="reagan-washington-national-airport-dca" class="level4">
<h4 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="reagan-washington-national-airport-dca">Reagan Washington National Airport (DCA)</h4>
<p>Reagan (a.k.a. National) is the most convenient. It is very close to downtown D.C. – near the Pentagon in Arlington, Virginia – and has its own Metro stop.</p>
<p>To get to College Park from Reagan by <a href="http://www.wmata.com/rail/maps/map.cfm">Metro</a>, take the Yellow Line, direction Fort Totten, to L’Enfant Plaza. At L’Enfant Plaza, change to the Green Line (direction Greenbelt). Get off the Green Line at <a href="http://ling.umd.edu/directions/#frommetro">College Park Station</a>. During the peak hours of the AM and PM commutes, this transfer is not necessary, and you can take the Yellow Line all the way to College Park. When using the DC Metro it is best to buy a reusable <a href="http://www.wmata.com/fares/smartrip/">SmarTrip</a> card. If instead you buy a new ticket for each ride, you will pay a $1 surcharge for for each ticket. One can also use <a href="https://www.wmata.com/fares/MobilePay/ApplePay.cfm">Apple Wallet</a> or <a href="https://www.wmata.com/fares/MobilePay/GooglePay.cfm">GPay</a> options. Taxi service to College Park from Reagan costs approximately $40.00, plus a tip. <a href="http://www.supershuttle.com/Locations/DCAAirportShuttleWashington.aspx">Super Shuttle</a> is also an option. In a shared van, the price is $28, plus $10 per additional person. Reagan is only about 15 miles from the University. But throughout work hours, traffic is terrible. The ride will take at least 30 minutes, but less than one hour.</p>
</section>
<section id="baltimore-washington-international-airport-bwi" class="level4">
<h4 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="baltimore-washington-international-airport-bwi">Baltimore-Washington International Airport (BWI)</h4>
<p>Flights to BWI are cheaper than flights to Reagan. It is a hub city for the discount carrier Southwest Airlines, which generates some price competition. BWI has mostly domestic connections, but also a few direct international connections (for example, to the UK and Germany).</p>
<p>There is weekday public bus service to BWI from the Greenbelt Metro Station, for only $7.50, on the <a href="http://www.wmata.com/bus/b30_brochure.cfm">B30 Metrobus</a> Metrobus (there is no service over the weekend). Greenbelt is just one stop beyond College Park on the <a href="http://www.wmata.com/rail/maps/map.cfm">Metro</a> Green Line. College Park is about 25 miles from BWI. Taxi service is therefore expensive, in the area of $70. The <a href="http://www.supershuttle.com/Locations/BWIAirportShuttleBaltimore.aspx">Super Shuttle</a> costs $32, plus $12 per additional person.</p>
</section>
<section id="washington-dulles-international-airport-iad" class="level4">
<h4 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="washington-dulles-international-airport-iad">Washington-Dulles International Airport (IAD)</h4>
<p>Dulles is the main international hub in the region, with direct connections from throughout the US, Europe, and Asia.</p>
<p>Dulles is 25 miles west of downtown D.C, however, and the 40 mile trip from Dulles to College Park is not easy. Options are taxi or shuttle van, or bus-and-metro combination. Taxi service to College Park costs approximately $80. The drive is at least 45 minutes, and most often one hour. <a href="http://www.supershuttle.com/Locations/IADAirportShuttleWashington.aspx">Super Shuttle</a> is another option: a shared van is $39, plus $10 per additional person. But be warned! Trips to College Park can be as much as three hours long: in dropping off several customers, the shuttle may follow a circuitous path, and traffic is generally terrible. The cheapest path is by <a href="http://www.wmata.com/rail/maps/map.cfm">Metro</a>, $11. Take the <a href="http://www.washfly.com/coach.html">Silver Line Express Bus</a> ($5) to <a href="http://silverlinemetro.com/wiehle-reston-east/">the Wiehle-Reston Metrorail Station</a>. From there take the Silver Line train, direction Largo Town Center, to <a href="http://www.wmata.com/rail/station_detail.cfm?station_id=82">L’Enfant Plaza</a>. At L’Enfant Plaza, transfer to the Green Line, direction Greenbelt, and get off in <a href="http://www.wmata.com/rail/station_detail.cfm?station_id=79">College Park</a>. Under ideal conditions, the combination of bus and Metro ride will talk 90 minutes. But you should plan for a two-hour trip (at least) to be cautious.</p>
<p>When using the DC Metro it is best to buy a reusable <a href="http://www.wmata.com/fares/smartrip/">SmarTrip</a> card. If instead you buy a new ticket for each ride, you will pay a $1 surcharge for for each ticket. One can also use <a href="https://www.wmata.com/fares/MobilePay/ApplePay.cfm">Apple Wallet</a> or <a href="https://www.wmata.com/fares/MobilePay/GooglePay.cfm">GPay</a> options.</p>
</section>
</section>
<section id="driving-to-college-park" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="driving-to-college-park">Driving to College Park</h3>
<section id="from-the-north" class="level4">
<h4 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="from-the-north">From the north</h4>
<p>Take I-95 South to exit 27 for I-495 West (“Silver Spring”). Immediately after this (very gentle) exit, follow signs for Route 1 South (“College Park”), Exit 25. The campus is about 2 miles down Route 1.</p>
</section>
<section id="from-the-south" class="level4">
<h4 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="from-the-south">From the south</h4>
<p>Take I-95 North to I-495, the Capital Beltway, which is a continuation of I-95. Continue North on I-95/I-495 toward Baltimore. Take Exit 25 for Route 1 South toward College Park. The campus is about 2 miles down Route 1.</p>
</section>
<section id="parking-info" class="level4">
<h4 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="parking-info">Parking Info</h4>
<p>A list of parking garages on campus is <a href="http://cvs.umd.edu/visitors/parking.html">here</a>. The lot closest to WSCLA is <a href="https://www.admissions.umd.edu/visit/unionlanegarage.php">Union Lane Garage</a>, which sits immediately to the west of the Stamp Student Union. Parking on campus is $15/day on weekdays and $5/day on weekends.</p>
<p>You can also park in town at the <a href="http://shopcollegepark.org/shops/downtown-parking-garage/">Yale Avenue Garage</a> for $0.75/hour, which will save you money on weekdays (13 hours will be $9.75), and on Sunday, when parking will be free. To get to WSCLA from this garage, follow the directions from Route 1 to Stamp above or <a href="https://www.google.com/maps/dir/Campus+Dr+%26+Campus+Drive,+College+Park,+MD+20740/Adele+H.+Stamp+Student+Union,+3972+Campus+Dr,+College+Park,+MD+20742/@38.9879537,-76.9444502,1424m/am=t/data=!3m2!1e3!4b1!4m14!4m13!1m5!1m1!1s0x89b7c6a498bfc655:0x6bb50ccbb6365a21!2m2!1d-76.9352583!2d38.9885485!1m5!1m1!1s0x89b7c4065ace9699:0xdc2bb57f0c8b153c!2m2!1d-76.9448867!2d38.9878244!3e2">here</a>.</p>
</section>
</section>
<section id="travel-by-train" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="travel-by-train">Travel by Train</h3>
<section id="amtrak-to-college-park" class="level4">
<h4 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="amtrak-to-college-park">Amtrak to College Park</h4>
<p><a href="http://www.amtrak.com/">Amtrak</a> makes two stops in the area, <a href="http://www.unionstationdc.com/">Union Station</a> in Washington, and <a href="http://wmata.com/rail/station_detail.cfm?station_id=68">New Carrollton Station</a> in Maryland.</p>
</section>
<section id="union-station-was" class="level4">
<h4 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="union-station-was">Union Station (WAS)</h4>
<p>Many trains stop at Union Station, which is on several Amtrak routes: the <a href="http://www.amtrak.com/servlet/ContentServer?c=AM_Route_C&amp;pagename=am%2FLayout&amp;cid=1241245664867">Acela Express</a>, <a href="http://www.amtrak.com/servlet/ContentServer?c=AM_Route_C&amp;pagename=am%2FLayout&amp;cid=1241245668597">Northeast Regional</a>, <a href="http://www.amtrak.com/servlet/ContentServer?c=AM_Route_C&amp;pagename=am%2FLayout&amp;cid=1241245667150">Vermonter</a>, <a href="http://www.amtrak.com/servlet/ContentServer?c=AM_Route_C&amp;pagename=am%2FLayout&amp;cid=1241245652139">Capitol Limited</a>, <a href="http://www.amtrak.com/servlet/ContentServer?c=AM_Route_C&amp;pagename=am%2FLayout&amp;cid=1241245652448">The Cardinal</a>, and <a href="http://www.amtrak.com/servlet/ContentServer?c=AM_Route_C&amp;pagename=am%2FLayout&amp;cid=1237608339450">Silver Service / Palmetto</a>. From Union Station it is easy to get to the University of Maryland by <a href="http://www.wmata.com/rail/maps/map.cfm">Metro</a>. Take the Red Line (direction Glenmont) to Fort Totten. At Fort Totten, transfer to the Green Line (direction Greenbelt). Get off at <a href="http://ling.umd.edu/directions/#frommetro">College Park Station</a>.</p>
</section>
<section id="new-carrollton-ncr" class="level4">
<h4 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="new-carrollton-ncr">New Carrollton (NCR)</h4>
<p>Relatively few trains stop at New Carrollton. It is served only by the<a href="http://www.amtrak.com/servlet/ContentServer?c=AM_Route_C&amp;pagename=am%2FLayout&amp;cid=1241245668597">Northeast Regional</a> and <a href="http://www.amtrak.com/servlet/ContentServer?c=AM_Route_C&amp;pagename=am%2FLayout&amp;cid=1241245667150">Vermonter</a> Routes. The <a href="http://www.wmata.com/bus/timetables/timetables-state.cfm?State=MD">F6 bus</a> from New Carrollton to Silver Spring stops at the University of Maryland. But this bus is not frequent. You may therefore want to take a taxi or ask a local friend for a ride. The station is about 6 miles from the University. The advantage of New Carrollton over Union Station is that this drive is the easier than the 8 miles through city traffic to Union Station.</p>
<!--Include social share buttons-->
<!--
AddToAny check more: https://www.addtoany.com/buttons/for/website
Using includes will make edits easier, will only need to add or remove button here if needed.
https://quarto.org/docs/authoring/includes.html
-->
<i>Share this post:</i>
<div class="a2a_kit a2a_kit_size_32 a2a_default_style">
<p><a class="a2a_dd" href="https://www.addtoany.com/share"></a> <a class="a2a_button_linkedin"></a> <a class="a2a_button_x"></a> <a class="a2a_button_facebook"></a> <a class="a2a_button_mastodon"></a> <a class="a2a_button_whatsapp"></a> <a class="a2a_button_wechat"></a> <a class="a2a_button_sina_weibo"></a> <a class="a2a_button_copy_link"></a> <a class="a2a_button_email"></a></p>
</div>
<script async="" src="https://static.addtoany.com/menu/page.js"></script>


</section>
</section>
</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>travel</category>
  <category>attending</category>
  <guid>https://hsp2025.github.io/posts/travel/</guid>
  <pubDate>Wed, 04 Sep 2024 04:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>
